

# Michael

### Backend Software Developer

12 December 1987



California



949-228-0695



michael hor vath 87@gmail.com

### About me –

Originally from Kansas, Michael has lived in eight states and two countries. Michael enjoys climbing, running, playing guitar and anything that gets him outside. He's been writing software for about seven years now, but he's been exploring since the day he could walk – perhaps even earlier.

# Python Figuring it out VIM Linux Whiteboarding CSS

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

### beliefs

Continual growth is key to enjoyment of life; challenge begets growth.

Passion is a must.

Software = Poetry + Math

### education

2006-2011 B.A. cum laude

University of Kansas

Psychology and Statistics

2002-2006 High school, 4.0 GPA

Shawnee Mission East HS

Extras: Diving, Soccer, Choir, Science Olympics

### awards

1997-2001 Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools

2005 Science Olympiad State Champion, Chemistry

2006 CalTech Signature Award, Excellence in Science and Mathematics

2016 Heart and Soul Award, Lawrence Ultimate Frisbee League

## experience

February 2022Software Engineer

Maxar Technologies

- Back-end development in Sanic micro-service architecture system. Refactoring for modularity and readability. - Functional and unit testing.

2021 - 2022 Lead Data Scientist

Fluxergy

- Design, development, testing and release of real-time quantitative diagnostic algorithms for PCR and lateral flow tests. - Study design, program evaluation, and data sampling.

2020 - 2021 Algorithms Engineer

Fluxergy

 Redesigned primary image-based PCR analysis algorithm, through all phases of QMS software development lifecycle.
 Designed, connected, and commodified business intelligence piplines across departments. Created real-time interactive dashboards and BI reports.

2018 - 2020 Software Engineer

Fluxergy

- Designed, developed, and maintained data-centric internal applications, run in decker ized cloud environments. Custom report generation for automatic recurring, user-built reports, with plugins for B1 integration.

2017 - 2018 Software Engineer

Embrace Healthwear

Data preprocessing, pipelining and analysis of motion-sensor high-frequency time-series data.

2015 - 2022 Personal Projects

- Neural net generator for exploring node generation, tuning and lifecycle of basic machine learning processes in Elixir. - High frequency trading algorithm development and back-testing.

### skills

2018-2022 Python, Django, Flask, Sanic, PHP, MySQL, Docker, LaTex, docker-compose, Git, Cloud resources (Azure and AWS), Database desgin, Elastic-search and Kibana, PowerBI, Javascript/HTML/CSS, CI/CD, Infrastructure

as code

2010-2020 Program evaluation, technical liaison, public speaking, regression analysis, ANOVA, MANOVA, optimization, structural equation modeling, busi-

ness intelligence.